(神楽)おいおいおい！
いや そうじゃなくて…｡
(銀時)ｸﾝｸﾝ… 腐ってるな｡
自分を安く売っちゃ ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙよ！
やれ 同棲だ できちゃっただ➡
やっぱり人間っていうのは➡
これ ｶﾋﾞだよな？
確かに➡
(新八)ﾎﾝﾄ 世の中 腐ってますよ｡
これ 白ｶﾋﾞみてえなのが
生えてんだよ｡
自分を律する精神がないと
終わりですよ！
ｶﾋﾞの生えた 古くさい考え方かも
しれないですけど➡
ｱｲﾄﾞﾙｸﾞﾙｰﾌﾟ 反侍のｺﾞｴﾓﾝが
できちゃった結婚だってさ｡
これ いつ買ったんだ？
賞味期限 切れてんだろ？
そう！ 女たちも
賞味期限とか気にしすぎね！
(お房)ﾊｧ… ﾊｧ…｡
ごめんね… ごめんね！
(お房)ごめんね…
必ず迎えにくるから｡
物事の筋道が揺らいでますよ｡
いや そうじゃなくてよ➡
♪♪～
おい いいかげんにしろよ！
腐ってんだよ これ!!
誰だよ出したの これ！
(新八/神楽)ﾎﾝﾄ 腐ってるよね～｡
あぁ 腐ってる！
お前らの頭が腐ってる!!
I'm sorry... I promise I'll come back for you.
…なんか だんだん➡
言うこと
聞かなくなってきたな ｱｲﾂら｡
特に新八からは 時々➡
Sorry... I'm sorry...
軽蔑のまなざし的な
視線を感じるときがあるな｡
１回 ﾔｷ入れとくか｡
神楽は… 逆に やられそうだな｡
Hey, hey, hey! Goemon, a member of the teen-idol group Hansamu, had a shotgun marriage.
(勘七郎)ばぶ～｡
This is rotten.
Really, this world has gone rotten. Cohabitation or shotgun marriages... People are losing their morals.
いや… ない｡
ないな これは ない｡
ったく
ﾊﾞｶ言ってんじゃねえっつ～の！
No, that's not what I meant. There's something in here that looks like mold.
(勘七郎)ばぶ あぶ～！
ぶっぶ～｡
This is mold, right?
Indeed.
いやいやいや ないって｡
It may be a moldy and outdated way of thinking,
あれは あれだったから
うん 大丈夫｡
but if we lose our discipline, it'll be the end of humanity.
これは ない！
(勘七郎)だぁ だぁ～！
No, that's not what I meant.
ないないない… ない！
これは ない！
When did you buy this? Isn't it past the expiration date?
だって あれだもん
あれは なんやかんやで➡
Right!
Women are too sensitive about their "expiration" date! They shouldn't sell themselves so cheap.
いろいろあって 総合するとない！
これは ないって!!
Hey, cut it out. This is rotten. Who bought this?
(勘七郎)ぶっ｡
だから～！
どぉ～!
(お登勢)朝から ｶﾞﾀｶﾞﾀうるせえ!!
It really is rotten!
You bet they are. Your brains are rotten.
Boy, they just don't listen anymore.
Especially Shinpachi, sometimes I feel he looks at me with contempt.
Maybe I should beat him into submission. Kagura...?
With her, it's the opposite--she'd beat me up.
[This is your child. Please raise him. I am exhausted and can no longer care for him.]
No. No way. This isn't happening.
Really. It's so ridiculous.
No way. That was just... Right...
It's all right. This can't be happening...
No, no, no, no, no! No way! This can't be happening! Not happening!
There's no way this is happening to me right now. Uh-uh! No way!
I said...!
Shut up, you idiot! It's too early for your crap!
[A naturally wavy-haired baby was left in front of Odd Jobs.]
[Gin-san is shocked by the unexpected discovery of an illegitimate child!!]
["Milk Should Be Served at Body Temperature"]
ばぶぅ…｡
腐ってる｡
You're rotten...
腐ってるね｡
You really are...
いいかげんな男とは
思ってたけど➡
I always knew you were good-for-nothing,
そのへんに種まいて➡
but I didn't think you could be so thoughtless as to plant a seed and just move on.
女ほったらかして
生きていけるような➡
性根の腐ったﾔﾂとは
思わなかったよ｡
だから！ ｵﾚは保健体育は
常に５だったんだってば｡
But I always got a "5" in PE. So, I know how to control myself.
[Note: School subjects in Japan are evaluated by numbers, 5 being the highest, like an "A".]
そんな失敗はしねえって｡
いや 保健体育は関係ないって｡
Well, this has nothing to do with PE.
とぼけないでくださいよ｡
Don't act stupid. His hair is soft like a cat's and wavy.
この ｸﾘｸﾘの猫っ毛
ふてぶてしい相貌➡
And that arrogant expression, too. Obviously inherited from you.
明らかに銀さんの遺伝ですよ！
ｵﾚは 天ﾊﾟｰの伝承者か!?
You're saying I passed on the naturally wavy hair trait? I'd never lay a trap like that on my own kid!
ｵﾚは子供に
こんな重荷は負わせねえ!!
遺伝子ねじ曲げてでも
ｻﾗｻﾗﾍｱのｶﾞｷを作る!!
I'd make a silky straight-haired kid, even if it meant untwisting my genes!
あぁ もう！
大きな声 出さないでよ｡
Come on!
Stop talking so loud. The baby will cry! Right, Silver J. Fox?!
子供が泣いちゃうでしょ
ね～ ｼﾙﾊﾞｰ･Ｊ･ﾌｫｯｸｽ！
やめてくんない？
その名前 やめてくんない!?
Can you stop it? Can you stop calling him by that name?
どうせ そのへんの ﾔﾝﾏﾏが➡
I bet his young mom just left him to go play pachinko. How annoying!
ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺに行きたくて
預けただけだろう｡
迷惑な話だぜ｡
Mr. Naturally-wavy hair is trying to dodge his responsibility.
天ﾊﾟｰが責任逃れしようと
してまちゅよ｡
He just doesn't know when to admit the truth, right, Ginraku?
[Note: Ginraku is written from the "Gin" in Gintoki and the "gura" in Kagura]
あきらめの悪いﾊﾟﾊﾟでしゅね 銀楽！
やめてくんない？
Will you stop it?! Stop calling him by that comic storyteller's name!
[Note: Many comic storytellers have a name that contains "raku."]
その 落語家みたいな名前
やめてくんない!?
ｴﾍﾍ… あっ やばい ぐずりだした｡
Oh, this is bad!
He's getting cranky.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｳﾝｺでも
もらしたんじゃないですか？
Did he poop in his pants or what?
違いますよ これ
たぶん お乳が欲しいんですよ｡
It doesn't look like it. He just wants some milk.
誰か～!! お乳の出る方は
いらっしゃいませんか～！
Someone! Does anyone have breast milk?
私 出してみるね
今なら出せる気がするね｡
Let me try. I feel like some might come out now.
出るわけ ねえだろう！
なに母性に目覚めてんの!?
No way!
Why are you bringing out your motherly instincts all of sudden?!
あぁ 私 出そう…
実は私 昨日から腹の調子が…｡
It might come out of mine. In fact, I've had an upset stomach since yesterday.
お前の ｳﾝｺで
何が解決するんだよ！
That's not where milk's made! That's called diarrhea!
He's drinking!
飲んだ！
飲みましたよ！
He really is!
あぁ ちゃんと吸ってるよ！
生きてるみたい!!
Wow, he's sucking really well! It's like he's real!
おい ｺｲﾂには
もう赤ん坊を抱かせるなよ｡
Hey! Don't let her carry the baby anymore.
ちょっと 私にも やらせるｱﾙよ！
Hey! Let me try it, too!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｶﾞｷが ｶﾞｷに触るなんて
100年 早いよ！
You're too young! Come back in a hundred years!
近頃は
男のほうが うまいんですよ…｡
These days, men can take better care of babies!
Leave it to me as the old woman! Old women are really good at this kind of thing.
ばばぁに任しときな！
ばばぁは得意なんだから
こんなんはさ｡
Hey, hey...
《おいおい…
なんか やばくねえか？
This is not good.
みんな なんか楽しそうだし…》
Everyone looks so happy...
なんだか こんなん
あったほうが いいだろう？
It never hurts to have one of these either. Really, what a troublesome baby.
ったく 世話焼かせる ｶﾞｷだよ｡
まったく…
だから嫌いなんですよ ｶﾞｷは｡
Really... That's why I hate little brats.
ﾍﾞﾛﾍﾞﾛﾊﾞｰ！
なんだ 全然 笑わないなぁ｡
Peek-a-boo!
What? He isn't laughing at all.
《なんか… ﾒﾛﾒﾛだし》
It seems... They're all going gaga over him.
よ～しよし 金時｡
All right, Kintoki. Don't become a loser like your father.
お前は親父みたいな人間に
なっちゃﾀﾞﾒだよ｡
万時 こっち向いて万時｡
Mantoki. Look over here, Mantoki.
銀楽 お母さんだよ 銀楽｡
Ginraku. It's your mother, Ginraku.
Sakata. Idiot Sakata.
坂田！ ｱﾎの坂田！
All these names are derived from my name!
《ぜ～んぶ ｵﾚにちなんでるし!!》
だぁ～!!
(お登世)あっ どこに行くんだい！
Ah! Where are you going?!
うぉ～！
あの野郎！ まさか
また捨てにいくつもりじゃ…！
That bastard! I wonder if he's going to abandon him again...
させるかっ！
(賀兵衛)あのぅ…｡
Over my dead body!!
Um...
(賀兵衛)すみません｡
Excuse me.
ちょっと お尋ねしたいことが…｡
I'd like to ask you something...
(沖田)捨て子… ですかい？
An abandoned child?
あぁ まっ そういうことで➡
Right. I'll leave the rest up to you guys, the police. Please take care of it.
あとは お前ら
おまわりさんに頼むわ ｼｸﾖﾛ｡
(沖田)おいおい
冗談はよしてくだせえ 旦那｡
Hey, hey... Are you kidding me, Mister?
(沖田)この坊主
旦那と ｸﾘｿﾂじゃありやせんか｡
You and this boy are like two peas in a pod. He's even got those dead fish eyes of yours.
この 死んだ目なんて 瓜二つだ｡
お前 知らねえの？
最近のｶﾞｷは みんな そうなんだ｡
Don't you know? Nowadays, all brats are like that.
ｹﾞｰﾑとか ﾈｯﾄ漬けで
外で遊んでねえからさ➡
It's because they're obsessed with video games and the Internet, and they don't play outside.
病んだ時代だよ｡
It's a really sick era.
Anyway, I don't know with whom you made this kid. Aren't you a stud, Mister?
しかし どこでこさえたか
知りやせんが➡
旦那も隅におけねえな…
この この！
沖田君… 旦那は こっちだ！
Okita-kun. Mister is over here. You're doing that on purpose, aren't you?!
わざとやってるだろ！
お前 わざとだろ？
まっ 旦那…
まさしく自分でまいた種は➡
Well, Mister... It means you must reap what you sowed.
自分で何とかしろってやつですよ｡
っつうことで
ｵﾚも公務に忙しいんで➡
Anyway,
I'm busy with official business, so let's just wrap this up.
この話は ここまでで…｡
(沖田)うわぁ～！
なんて ｵﾚの周りは
話を聞かねえﾔﾂばかりなんだ！
Why am I surrounded by people who won't listen to my story?
そんなに似てるか？ ｵﾚたち｡
(勘七郎)あぶ～｡
Do we look so much alike? The two of us?
(お妙)あら… 銀さん？
Oh? Gin-san?
Are you working now? You really do work hard.
(お妙)お仕事中ですか？
ご苦労さまです｡
おっ おぅ… やぁ あの あれだ｡
O-Oh... Well... That's right...
Babysitting... I mean, I was asked to do something like...
子守みたいなの頼まれてな｡
(お妙)あっ
ちょっと待って 銀さん｡
See-ya
Hey, wait, Gin-san!
あずきﾊﾞｰとﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭください｡
One Azuki Bar and Baagen-Dash, please.
(店主)ねえよ… そんな高えｱｲｽ｡
いいよ ちょっと おかまいなく｡
We don't usually have such fancy ice cream.
Well, don't mind us...
あんだろ？ ｺﾝﾋﾞﾆに｡
(店主)買ってきます｡
They have it at the convenience store, don't they?
I'll go buy it.
ﾎﾝﾄいいから～！
It's all right. Seriously!
《このままじゃ
なに言われるかわかんねえ！》
I gotta get outta here! If she finds out, I'm not sure what she'll do!
Ah, Gin-san!
銀さん！
待てって言ってんだろうが!!
I said
wait!!
大納言！
Daina bomb?
[Note: "Daina bomb" is a play on the word "dainagon" which is a kind of red bean sweet.]
Ah...
あっ…｡
おい 大丈夫か？
Hey... Are you all right?
(さっちゃん)そうなんだ…
そうだったんだ｡
I see...That was it... You two were...a couple...
(さっちゃん)あなたたち
そういう関係だったんだ｡
ﾊﾞｶみたい ｱﾀｼ｡
何も知らないで 一人で…｡
I feel so stupid... I didn't know anything... I was the only one...
(さっちゃん)まるでﾋﾟｴﾛだわ！
I was like...a buffon...
そうやって ｱﾀｼの気持
もてあそんで楽しんでたんだ｡
You played with my feelings and strung me along... While you two were busy making a baby together.
もう２人は とっくに
子供をこさえる間柄だったのに｡
(お妙)猿飛さん なに言ってるの？
頭 かち割るわよ！
Sarutobi-san, what are you talking about? I'll knock your brains out.
もういいわ… もう ﾎﾝﾄにいい！
ﾊﾞｶみたい！ ｱﾀｼ ﾎﾝﾄにﾊﾞｶみたい!!
That's enough. It really is! I look so stupid. I really do!
みたいじゃなくてﾊﾞｶだろう？
お前 ﾎﾝﾄ ﾊﾞｶだろう？
You don't "look stupid," you are stupid! You really are stupid, aren't you?
どんなに さげすまれても
もう何も気持よくないわ！
No matter how much disdain you show for me, I don't feel good anymore!
ＳＭﾌﾟﾚｲは もう終わり！
Our little S&M game is over!!
ｵﾚが いつ
ＳＭﾌﾟﾚｲをしましたか！
When did I ever do S&M with you?
ｱﾝﾀたちなんか
ﾊﾞﾝﾊﾞﾝ ﾊﾞﾝﾊﾞﾝ子宝に恵まれて➡
You two have tons of children and have a big family!
大家族になればいいのよ！
And live in a house with many holes in the paper sliding doors!
[Note: Kids love to poke holes in paper sliding doors.]
障子が穴だらけの家に
住めばいいのよ！
さようなら！
勝手に お幸せに!!
Good-bye! Best wishes, whatever!
って させるか～！
But...
I won't let you do that!
(お妙)何だよ ｺｲﾂもう!!
Oh, please, you're a one-woman soap opera! You're a B-movie script!
一人で ﾄﾞﾗﾏやれるよ
一人で映画 撮れるよ！
残念だったわね お妙さん｡
I pity you, Otae-san.
女は子供産んだ瞬間から
女として見てもらえなくなるの｡
The moment a woman gives birth, she isn't seen as a woman anymore! She's just a family member!
家族なの！
あなたは もう女じゃない!!
You're no longer a woman!
勝手に勝負から
脱落していったのよ！
You've taken yourself out of the competition! Way to go!
お疲れさま～！
だから どの勝負よ!!
What kind of battle are you talking about?!
産んでねえって言ってんだろ！
I said I didn't give birth! Who wants to have a child with that pathetic samurai?!
誰が あのﾀﾞﾒ侍の子なんて産むか！
だったら あの子を
どう説明するつもり？
Then how do you explain that boy? He looks just looks like him! His natural wavy hair and eyes!
ｸﾘｿﾂじゃない！
天ﾊﾟ-といい あの目といい…!!
He's just like him!
ｸﾘｿﾂじゃない！
知らないわよ｡
I really don't know! At least I'm sure he's not my child!
少なくとも 私の子供じゃ
ないことだけは確かよ！
ねぇ 銀さん｡
何とか言ってやって…｡
Right, Gin-san? Say something to her!
えっ？
(お妙)ｸﾘｿﾂじゃねえか！
Like father, like son!!
まさか 隠し子がいるなんて
最低だわ！
That's your bastard child all right. And you call yourself a samurai? For shame.
見損ないました！ 新ちゃんにも
仕事 辞めさせますから｡
I'll make Shin-chan quit his job. Let's go, Sarutobi-san.
行きましょう 猿飛さん｡
なんだ…｡
Why? Why won't anybody around here listen to me?
なんで ｵﾚの周りは 人の話を
聞かねえﾔﾂばかりなんだ？
それは ｱﾝﾀも人の話を
聞かねえからです｡
Because you never listen to other people.
あぁ… そうか…｡
Oh...I see...
(お登勢)悪いけど知らないね
こんな娘…｡
I'm sorry, but I don't know. I've never seen a lady like this before.
(お登勢)見たこともない｡
(賀兵衛)そうですか｡
I see.
(賀兵衛)申し訳ありません｡
Oh, I'm sorry. I was so forward. I still haven't introduced myself.
いきなり名乗りもせず
ぶしつけに…｡
あの 申し遅れました｡
私 橋田 賀兵衛と申しまして➡
I'm Kahei Hashida. I run a store here in Kabukicho.
この かぶき町で
店を開かせてもらってます｡
えっ あの大財閥の？
(神楽)なに それ｡
Huh? That big corporation?
What's that?
ほら 万事屋からも見えるじゃん｡
あのでっかい建物｡
You see? You can see it from the Yorozuya. That huge building!
(お登勢)で いったい
何があったんだい？
So, what happened?
実は 先日
私のたった一人の大切な孫が➡
Well... The other day, my one and only precious grandson suddenly disappeared.
突然
いなくなってしまいまして…｡
(お登勢)かどわかし？
えっ？
A kidnapping?
断定はできませんが まだ歩くのも
おぼつかない子ゆえ おそらく…｡
I don't know for sure, but he just started walking, so he probably...
それで… 心当たりを
あたってみたところ その娘が…｡
I have reason to believe that lady in the photograph was involved.
こんなきれいな人が…｡
奉行所へは？
A beautiful lady, like this?
Did you report it to the police?
それが なにぶん
込み入った事情がございまして➡
Well, the circumstances are a bit complicated, so I don't want to make this matter public.
あまり 公には…｡
事情が事情だし そんなこと
言ってる場合じゃないだろう｡
But under the circumstances, you really shouldn't be worried about your privacy.
(賀兵衛)えぇ
そうなんですが なんとも…｡
Right... That's probably true, but...
どうか この娘を見かけたら➡
Please... If you see this lady, just contact me.
連絡だけでもいいので
ご協力 願います｡
I'm asking for your cooperation. And here's a photo of my grandson...
あの 孫のほうの写真も…｡
(お房)すみません！
Excuse me. Is anybody here?
(お房)いないんですか？
(お登勢)おい こっちだよ｡
Hey, over here. How can I help you?
何か用かい？
あぁ なんか
自分に自信がなくなってきたぜ｡
Ah...
I feel like I've lost my confidence. Hey, you. You're not really my son, are you?
お前 ﾎﾝﾄに
ｵﾚの息子なんじゃねえだろう？
はぷん｡
本当の親は どこにいるんだ？
Where're your real parents? Please release me from this responsibility.
早く ｵﾚを解放してくれ｡
(勘七郎)べっ！
お父さ～ん って呼んでみ｡
Call your father. Say "Daddy."
お父さ～んって…｡
(勘七郎)ばぶぶ｡
(志士)そこの者 ちと待たれい！
You there. Stop right now.
ん？
Hey, hey. You've got lots of fathers...
おいおい ずいぶん
たくさん お父さんがいるんだな｡
[OTOSE SNACK HOUSE]
Stop! Let me go!
(お房)やめて！ 離して!!
(賀兵衛)この性悪女が！
You, wicked woman!
(賀兵衛)とうとう見つけたぞ！
I've finally I found you.
Where's Kanshichiro? Tell me!
勘七郎を どこへやった？ 言え！
この女…｡
This woman...
(賀兵衛)立場をわきまえんか！
Remember who you are!
おいおい
ちょっと やりすぎじゃないか？
Hey, hey. Aren't you going a little overboard? She can't speak unless you stop that!
そんなんじゃ
しゃべるもんも しゃべれないよ｡
すみません…
つい興奮してしまって…｡
Forgive me. I got too worked up.
But from now on, it's a family matter, so we'll deal with it ourselves.
ですが ここからは
家族の問題ゆえ➡
私たちで解決します｡
お騒がせして
申し訳ありませんでした…｡
I'm sorry...
...for all the fuss.
Otose-san...
お登勢さん…｡
(神楽/ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)あぁ～っ!!
Oh!
(お登勢)どうしたんだい？
これ あの じじいが➡
What?
This is the person the old man was looking for.
捜してるっていってた
孫の写真｡
A photo of his grandson.
Isn't this good, kore?
[Note: Konohamaru of Naruto ends many of his sentences with "kore."]
えぇっ!?
ねぇ ﾔﾊﾞｲんじゃないですか これ！
銀さん
ﾔﾊﾞｲんじゃないんすか これ！
Is Gin-san all right, kore?
Could it be Gin-san is involved in some sort of trouble, kore?
変なことに 巻き込まれてるんじゃ
ないすか これ～!!
えっ？ 誘拐？ なにが？
Huh?
Kidnapping? What? Who? Where?
誰が？ どこで？
(志士)とぼけても ﾑﾀﾞだ｡
It's useless. Don't play dumb.
ｷｻﾏ…
あの女の愛人か 何かだろう？
You're that woman's lover or something, aren't you?
２人で共謀して
賀兵衛様の孫をさらい➡
You two kidnapped the grandson of Kahei-sama in some kind of conspiracy.
橋田屋の財産を 狙うつもりだな？
お～い なに言ってんの？
And you're trying to take Hashidaya's fortune, aren't you?
Hey, what are these people talking about?
この人たち｡
あぼん！
Hey, you! What are you talking about?
お前 なに言ってんの？ お前｡
I was told to capture the suspect alive, but it doesn't matter. It's a man. Kill him.
生きて捕らえよとのことだが
男なら 関係あるまい｡
(志士)斬り捨ててしまえ！
おいおい お～い
ｵﾚ 全然 関係ないから！
Hey, hey, hey! I'm not your problem!
酔った勢いで ｵﾚのﾊｰﾄは
お前の人質～！ とか➡
I just found this kid outside my door. I do odd jobs! I don't know the first thing about kidnapping!!
言ったかもしんないけど
関係ないから！
Then give us that baby back!
ならば その赤子を よこせ!!
待～て待て 焦るな…｡
そんなに欲しけりゃ 喜んで…｡
Hold on. Don't rush.
If you want, I'd be happy to...
♪♪～
If you won't give him back, we'll take him by force!
渡す気がなければ
力づくで奪うぞ！
かかれ!!
(志士たち)うぉぉぉ～っ!!
Get him!
I said...
だ～から！ 知らねえって
言ってんだろうが～!!
I don't know anything about it!
I'll give him back to you... You can take the brat!
返すぜ！ こんなｶﾞｷ!!
You bastard! What did you do?!
野郎 なんてﾏﾈを…！
拾え!!
Catch him!!
♪♪～
You have an interesting fighting technique.
(似蔵)おもしろいｹﾝｶのしかたを
する男だな…｡
守る戦いに 慣れているのか？
I wonder if you must be used to fighting to protect someone.
お前らのような 物騒な連中に
子育てはﾑﾘだ｡
Dangerous people like you can't raise a child. Get out of my way. It's time for his milk.
どけ ﾐﾙｸの時間だ｡
ｸｯｸｯｸｯｸｯ… いい… いいよ ｱﾝﾀ…｡
Good ...You're good.
The smell of the beast... You can't hide it. You smell like the beast and so does that brat.
獣の におい… 隠しきれない
獣の においがするよ｡
あの人と同じ…｡
It's no fun fighting a one-armed opponent. I'll let you go.
片腕で やり合うには
惜しいやねえ…｡ 行きな｡
♪♪～
Okada!
(志士)岡田～!!
ｷｻﾏ なにやっとるか！
You, what are you doing?!
追え！ 逃がすな～!!
After him! Don't let him out of your sights!
(似蔵)…ﾌｯ｡
Oh, dear!
(家政婦)あ～ もう
きったないわね～！
It's so dirty! I wonder why men always dirty the urinal like this.
男って どうして こんなに
便器 汚すのかしら…｡
Especially on the left side.
しかも 左ばっかり！
(家政婦)だいたい 男は➡
I hear most men point left.
みんな 左向きらしいわよ｡ 稀に➡
It's rare for men to point right, and it's the sign that they'll become the ruler of the kingdom.
右向きの持ち主も
いるらしいけど➡
それは 天下取りの相なのよ｡
They say Toyotomi Hideyoshi pointed to the right.
豊臣 秀吉も 右だったって｡
Oh, my! My husband points to the right. He'll become the ruler!
や～だ ｳﾁの旦那 右向きよ｡
天下取りだわ！
Toilets are disgusting lately too. It's like, "Which way do their butt-holes face?"
個室のほうも ひどいのよね 最近｡
ｹﾂの穴 どこ向いてんだ？
みたいな…｡
I know, huh? It's probably those ronin our master hired.
あれ あれでしょう？
最近 旦那様が雇ってる➡
浪人たちの仕業でしょう？
Really. Don't they know how to use a toilet?! I don't know if they're exclusionist rebels or what, but come on.
…ったく 厠の使い方も
知らねえのかってえの！
攘夷志士だか なんだか
知らないけどさ！
And who knows what our master is up to behind the scenes.
(家政婦)旦那様も
裏で なにやってるか➡
知れたもんじゃないわよ｡
なんか ｳﾜｻじゃ➡
The rumor is his grandson, Kanshichiro-sama, was kidnapped.
孫の 勘七郎様
さらわれたとかいう話だし…｡
ﾔﾊﾞｲことに
首 突っ込んでんじゃないの？
I wonder if he was involved in some bad business.
You're wrong. It heard Ofusa did it.
ｱﾝﾀ 違うわよ｡ あれは あの
お房の仕業らしいわよ｡
Huh? Is that so? Oh, no! That lady would do something like that?
そうなの!?
やだ あの子 そんなこと…｡
Well, after she was treated so badly, it couldn't be helped. Because she...
まぁ でも
あんな仕打ち 受けたんじゃ➡
しかたないんじゃない？
だって あの子…｡
(物音)
(２人)曲者～!!
(ﾄﾞｱを蹴る音)
Who's there?!
(長谷川)ｷﾞｬｰｰｯ!!
な なにすんだ ｸｿばばあども！
Wh-What are you doing, old women?! Don't look! Don't look at me!
見ないで！ ｵﾚを見ないで！
(家政婦)ｷｬｯ！
Kya! It's just some guy, and what a stinker!
(家政婦)曲者じゃなくて
くさ者だったわ～！
(家政婦)ｷｬｯ！
新入りの 長谷川さんだったわ！
Kya! It's Hasegawa, the new guy!
ｷｬｰｯじゃねえよ！
かわいくねえんだよ ｸｿばばあ!!
Stop saying "Kya!" It doesn't sound cute, you old hags!
(家政婦)ｷｬｰｯ！
左曲がりだったわ～！
Kya! His points to the left!
Kya! His curves more!
(家政婦)ｷｬｰｯ！ ｳﾁの旦那より
きつめのｶｰﾌﾞ 描いてたわ～！
Hey! Close the door! Close it! Please, close it!
おい 閉めろ！ 閉めて！
お願い 閉めてくださ～い！
Damn it!
(長谷川)ｸｿ～ｯ！ 使用人なんて
やるんじゃなかった！
I shouldn't have taken this job as a janitor! There aren't any hot little maids here!
(長谷川)かわいいﾒｰﾄﾞなんて
どこにも いやしない｡
There're only old women!
(長谷川)ばばあ
ばっかりじゃねえか！
Hey! Just keep walking.
(志士)おい！ さっさと歩け！
(長谷川)んっ？
Huh?
That is...the girl those old women were just talking about...
《あれは
さっき ばばあたちが言ってた…》
♪♪～
《おいおい… ｺｲﾂは➡
Hey, hey... This isn't the sort of place I should stay too long.
あんまり 長居するところじゃ
なさそうだなぁ…》
(神楽)だが この仕事やめて
どうする？
But what are you going to do if you quit this job? Are you going back to your loafer life?
(神楽)また ﾌﾟｰの生活に戻るのか？
《そうだ… いつも ｵﾚは そうだ｡
That's right. I'm always like this.
ちょっと 嫌なことがあったら
すぐ 仕事 変えて➡
When I come across something I don't like, I quit. Escaping is becoming my habit.
逃げｸﾞｾが ついちゃってる…》
That's right. He's a totally useless man, a DORK. He oughta kill himself.
(神楽)そのとおりだ｡
まるで ﾀﾞﾒな男 ﾏﾀﾞｵだ｡
(神楽)そうだ 死のう｡
《いやいや いや！ おかしいぞ｡
No, no, no. That's messed up. Why do I have to kill myself?
なんで 死ぬの？
おかしいぞ 今の…｡
That wasn't right. I mean, death's no trip to Kyoto.
そうだ 京都 行こう じゃ
ないんだからさ…》
No, no, no. You'd better die. There won't be anything good in your future if you live, uh-huh.
いやいや いや 死んどけって｡
どうせ この先 生きていたって
ろくなことないｱﾙ｡
"Uh-huh..." What? Huh?
ｱﾙって なんだよ？
…って なにしてんだ ﾃﾒｴら!!
What are you doing, you guys?!
お前か！ 人の頭に
変なﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ流してたﾔﾂは!!
Are you the one adding the weird narration and filling my head with such suicidal thoughts?!
Why are you here?!
なんで
こんなところに いるんだよ!!
We're housekeepers.
家政婦ｱﾙね｡
長谷川さんこそ➡
How about you? What are you doing here? Did you change jobs again?
なんで
こんなところに いるんですか？
また 転職ですか？
(長谷川)また って なんだよ！
What do you mean "again"?! Why are you giving me that look?!
(長谷川)なんだよ その目は！
まぁ ちょうどいっか｡
Oh, well. Good timing. Hasegawa-san, can you show us around?
長谷川さん ちょっと ﾎﾞｸらを➡
案内してくれませんか？
案内？
Show you around?
(志士)おのれ～ どこへ行った！
Damn him! Where did he go?
まだ 遠くへは行ってないはずだ！
捜せ!!
He can't be far away! Find him!
Hey, they're gone.
(桂)おい 行ったぞ｡
行ったと言っている｡
I said they're gone.
I said they're gone!
行ったと言ってるだろうが！
There's no way I can hide in there!
んなとこ 隠れられっかぁ！
Oh! You were hiding over there, after all.
あっ なんだ｡ 結局
そっちに隠れたのか｡
結局もｸｿも➡
Whatever. There's no way I could hide in there! Are you stupid? I bet you are.
ﾊﾅから そんなところに
隠れられるわけねえだろ！
ﾊﾞｶか お前｡ ﾊﾞｶだろ｡
ﾊﾞｶじゃない 桂だ!!
I'm not stupid, I'm Katsura!
(桂)銀時 ｱﾚは➡
Gintoki, they're probably exclusionist ronin.
おそらく 攘夷浪士だ｡
And the Hashidaya they mentioned is one of the biggest corporations in Edo.
そして あの 連中の
いっていた 橋田屋とは➡
あの 江戸でも 屈指の
巨大企業のことだろう｡
何か知ってるのか？
Do you know anything about it?
(桂)橋田 賀兵衛
という男は曲者でな｡
Kahei Hashida is a dangerous man.
攘夷浪士たちを 援助する
かわりに ﾔﾂらを闇で動かし➡
He supports the exclusionist ronin so he can move them around behind the scenes.
今では 一商人とは思えんほどの➡
That's why he became so powerful. It's not just an ordinary businessman.
権力を有しているらしい｡
(稲妻の音)
なんで そんな ﾔﾂの
孫が ｵﾚのところに…｡
Why did a man like that's grandson come to me?
さては 貴様 賀兵衛の
ところの娘と ﾆｬﾝﾆｬﾝ…｡
I guess you did "nyan nyan" with one of the girls at Kahei's place.
I already told you, I didn't! And what's "nyan nyan"?
だから 違うって言ってんだろう！
何 ﾆｬﾝﾆｬﾝって！ お前 不倫だよ！
That's an outdated word! Did you mean Yuyake?
夕焼けか！
しかし この ふてぶてしさ➡
Anyway, look at his arrogant face. He's definitely identical to you!
どう見ても お前とそっくりだぞ！
It's the job of a baby to cry. But you're ignoring your duties, slacker?!
赤子は 泣くのが
仕事だというのに｡
職務放棄か ｷｻﾏ！ ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ…｡
What kind of childcare is that?!
どんな あやしかただぁっ！
You've got to be kidding! If he starts crying now...
冗談じゃねえよ｡
こんな時に 泣き喚かれてみろ｡
Well, I'd just throw him into the river.
ﾎﾝﾄ 川に ぶん投げるところだぜ｡
(勘七郎)だばん｡
おぅ そうだ｡
Oh, yeah. The only time a man should cry is if his hair's permed too tight.
男はな ﾊﾟｰﾏに 失敗したとき
以外は 泣いちゃいけねえよ｡
お前は そのへん 見込みがあるぞ｡
You have good prospects in that area.
新八よりある｡
おい 銀時…｡
Even more than Shinpachi.
Hey, Gintoki... Look down.
下 下…｡
あ？
Huh?
(桂)上は 大丈夫だが
下は 泣き虫らしい｡
It looks like his upper part is all right, but his lower part gets wet easily.
(長谷川)ｵｲｵｲ やべえよ！
Hey, hey! This is bad!
It doesn't look like the old man of Hashidaya is a harmless old businessman!
橋田屋のｵｯｻﾝ ただの
商人じゃねえんだって！
なんか 黒い噂の絶えねえ
危ねえ ｵｯｻﾝなんだってよ！
He's more like a dangerous man with a dark rumor!
な 帰ろう！ ｵｼﾞｻﾝと帰ろう！
酢昆布 買ってあげるからさ！
Let's go home! Let's go home with this old man! I'll buy you some pickled seaweed!
I can't turn back now after hearing that.
そんな話 聞いたら
余計に帰れないですよ｡
やっぱり 何か裏があるよ これは｡
As I thought, there's got to be something going on behind the scenes.
酢昆布くらいで 釣られる
尻軽女と思ったか この野郎！
You thought I was some kind of hussy you could buy with pickled seaweed, huh, bastard?!
何個だ！ 酢昆布
何個で釣るつもりだった？
How many? How much pickled seaweed were you going to offer me?
まさか４個か？ ４個も
くれるんじゃないだろうな？
Don't tell me four! You were not going to give me only four?!
Kagura-chan, please be quiet.
神楽ちゃん 静かにして｡
ここですか？ あの女の人が➡
Is this the place? Is this the room they brought that woman to?
連れ込まれた部屋は？
おい 何個だ!?
Hey, how many?! Just say it. It's not like I'm interested or anything...
言うだけ 言うてみ｡
別にほしくないけどさ｡
(勘七郎)だぁ…｡
お前 右曲がりじゃねえか｡
[Diaper]
Oh, yours points to the right. You'll become somebody big in the future. Good for you!
将来 大物になるぞ｡ よかったな｡
(勘七郎)むぅ｡
なんだ なんだ？
What? What? Don't feel bad about wetting your pants.
小便 たれたくらいで
落ち込むんじゃねえよ｡
Those parts of a man have a will of their own. Something like this can happen.
男は 上と下が
別の生き物だからよ｡
こんなこともあるさ｡
にゃ…｡
There you go.
これでよしっと｡
Really...
ﾊｧ… ったく｡
I was mistaken for a dad and for a kidnapper... Today is my unlucky day.
親父に 間違われたり
誘拐犯に 間違われたり➡
厄日だ 今日は｡
(勘七郎)なふっ｡
Oh, sorry, sorry. It's your unlucky day, too. We've both got it rough, don't we?
あぁ 悪い 悪い｡
お前のほうが厄日か｡
お互い 大変だな｡
Oh, well. But as long as we're alive, there'll be days like this. For you...
まぁ でも 生きてりゃな
こういう日もある｡
ｵﾒｴも これから 人生でもっと➡
...there'll be many more hardships in life.
大変なことが いろいろ 起こるよ｡
Eighty percent of life is made up of hardships.
人生の80ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄは
厳しさで できてんだ｡
いや ﾎﾝﾄに…｡
Seriously...
俺なんか いっつも
こんなんばっかりさ｡
Stuff like this happens to me all the time.
でも 悪いことばかりじゃねえよ｡
But it's not all bad.
こういう１日の終わりに
飲む酒は うまいんだよ｡
At the end of a day like today, sake tastes great.
全部 終わったら
一緒に １杯やろうか｡
When everything is over, shall we have a drink together?
まふっ｡
All right... Shall we go?
よし… 一丁いくか！
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
(志士)ｵﾗｯ！ さっさと吐け！
Come on! Spill it, already!
Where's Kanshichiro-sama? You'll be released of your responsibility if you tell us.
勘七郎様は どこだ！
吐けば 楽になるぞ！
え！ なんとか言え！
Hey! Say something!
(賀兵衛)強情な女よ｡
What a stubborn woman.
I have no idea why Kantaro loves this slutty, flithy woman.
勘太郎も こんな薄汚れた➡
卑しい女のどこに惚れたのやら…｡
(賀兵衛)人の息子をたぶらかし➡
You seduced my son and killed him.
死なせたうえに
その子をさらうとは…｡
And you abducted his child... You, wicked woman!
この 性悪女め！
You guys are the ones who abducted Kanshichiro.
勘七郎様をさらったのは
あなたたちのほうでしょう？
あの子は 私の子です｡
誰にも渡さない！
He's my son. I won't let anyone take him from me!
(賀兵衛)お前のような
女から 橋田家の者が➡
It's a shame a woman like you bore a child from the Hashida family.
生まれただけでも
恥ずべきだというのに…｡
勘七郎に母親はいらん｡
Kanshichiro doesn't need a mother. I'll raise him as a son and true heir.
あの子は 私が 橋田家の
跡取りとして 立派に育てる｡
(賀兵衛)どうしても
言わぬというならば｡
If you won't say anything...
We'll have to get physical...
その体に聞くまでよ…｡
ﾔﾊﾞｲですよ 長谷川さん｡
This is bad, Hasegawa-san.
(志士)おい！ そこで何してる！
Hey, what are you doing there?
使用人か？
Housekeepers?
あ あれでございます｡
Um... That's right. Th-These two are the new housekeepers...
こ この者たち ２人
新入りでございまして…｡
So I'm showing them around the building.
あの… ﾋﾞﾙを
案内していたところでして｡
そうでごぜえます ご主人様｡
That's right, master.
Well, we're not your "master."
(志士)いや 俺たち
なんだ？
ご主人じゃないから｡
What? I thought men like to hear that kind of word, don't they?
なんか こんなん言われた
ほうが 嬉しいんだろ 男は？
ﾀﾞﾒだよ 神楽ちゃん ﾀﾞﾒ｡
そんなこと 言ったら！
No, no, Kagura-chan! No! Don't say that!
それじゃ 私は失礼して…｡
(似蔵)待ちな｡
Then, please excuse me...
Wait.
くさいねぇ｡ ﾈｽﾞﾐくさい
嘘つきｽﾊﾟｲのにおいだね｡
It stinks. I smell a lying spy with the stench of a rat.
(似蔵)今日は いろんな
においと出会える日だね｡
I seem to be smelling a lot of odd things today.
But right now I'm in the mood for the smell of blood and steel!
(似蔵)でも そろそろ 鉄くさい➡
血のにおいが嗅ぎたく
なってきたところさね｡
やり合ってくれるかい？
Will you fight...
この人斬り似蔵と…｡
...Nizo, the butcher?
ﾌｯ…｡
何事だ？
(破壊音)
What's the meaning of this?
Sorry to interrupt your fun.
こいつは
お楽しみちゅう すみませんね｡
ちょいと怪しい
ﾈｽﾞﾐを見つけたもんで｡
But I just found some suspicious rats.
(神楽/新八)いたた…｡
ん？
Huh? I saw you guys at Otose-dono's place.
そなたたちは
お登勢殿のところにいた｡
おやおや… こんなところまで➡
Oh, my! You followed me here. You're nosy people.
ついてくるなんて
お節介な人たちだ｡
私事ゆえ これ以上は➡
I told you this was a personal matter, so I don't need your help.
お手伝い いらぬ
と申したはずですが｡
心配いりませんよ｡
Don't worry. We came here for something personal, too.
僕らも私事できてるもんで…｡
それにしても 孫思いの
おじいちゃんにしては➡
By the way, Don't you think you're going too far even for a devoted grandfather, Kahei-san?
やりすぎじゃないですか
賀兵衛さん｡
You guys are more than just nosy.
あなた方も ただの
お節介にしては やりすぎですぞ｡
世の中には 知らぬ
ほうが いいこともある｡
There are things you're better off not knowing about in this world.
♪♪～
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
Are you asking me if I made an "apo?"
What's an "apo"? Huh? Could it be a fruit from the northern area, like a "Fuji Apple"?
The next episode... "If You Want to Meet Someone, Get an Appo First."
[Shinpachi and the others are in a critical pinch. And what will be the fate of Kanshichiro?!]
[Feared as "Nizo the Butcher". The sunglasses swordsman, Nizo Okada.]
♬～(ﾃｰﾏ音楽)
♬～